We are in the most expensive city in America
저희는 현재 미국에서 가장 비싼 도시에 와 있습니다.
New York City
바로 뉴욕이죠!
We just checked out a room here
저희는 방금 저기 호텔방을 체크아웃했는데요.
that was ten thousand dollars a night
하루에 무려 천 삼백만원이나 됩니다.
how do these people afford this
어떻게 사람들이 여기에서 머무는게 가능한지
today we're gonna find out
오늘 저희가 알아보겠습니다.
by going up to New Yorkers and asking them
뉴요커들한테 가서 물어볼거에요
What do y'all do for a living?
무슨일을 하는지
what  kind of stuff do you guys do in New York
뉴욕에서 어떤 종류에 일을 하는지요
What was your career?
직업이 무엇이었나요?
Ship owning.
배 소유주요
What? Really? You own ships?
뭐요? 진짜요? 배를 가지고 있다구요?
Yes mostly tankers
네 대부분 탱커쉽 (수송/저장) 들이요
and you bought and sold tanker?
탱커를 사고 팔고 한 건가요?
Yes It is.
네 맞아요.
Is that very lucrative of a career?
직업으로서 수익이 괜찮나요?
There are good years and very challenging years
좋은 날도 있고 아주 어려운 날들도 있죠
It's the only city in the world
여기가 세계에서 유일한 도시예요.
We could have started that business
그런 사업을 시작할 수 있는.
Very impressive
엄청나네요.
I sell farmland at auction.
경매에서 농지를 팝니다.
we're selling 40 different states.
40개 주에 팔고 있죠.
We sell quite a bit of land in Texas
텍사스에도 상당히 많이 팔았죠
I love Texas. Texas is a great state.
텍사스 너무 좋아요. 대단한 주예요.
Is that a lucrative career selling farmland?
농지를 파는건 수익성이 좋은 직업인가요?
It's a good good career. Excellent career.
좋은 직업이죠. 훌륭한 경력!
What do you do in New York?
뉴욕에서 뭐하세요?
I do tech sales for a company called Okta.
옥타라고 하는 회사에서 기술영업 하요.
I'm a product manager at a property tech company as well.
나도 부동산 기업에서 프로덕트 매니저로 일하고 있소.
What are the range of salaries at these kind of tech companies?
거 테크쪽에서 일하면 샐러리가 대충 어떻게 됩니까?
Upward is like three to four hundred in a year.
위로는 한 연 4~5억 받죠~
But I know someone who make around like 120.
근디 한 1억 6천밖에 못보는 놈도 봤습죠.
Dude, it's all over the place like depending on the job
형씨, 일에 따라 천차만별 아닌갑소
As a product manager, I'd say the low end is
프로덕트 매니저면, 낮게 보면 한
probably around hundred but guys at Google
1억 3천정도 되올시고, 구글러놈들은
are probably making like 400 thousand
아마도 5억 5천정도는 땡길거요.
I'm a graphic designer
난 그래픽 디자이너 올시다.
I now work at Google
구글에서 일하죠
Like generally, how much do you make range?
보통 연봉 범위가 어느 정도나 됩니까
When I first moved I think I made like 80 grand a year
내가 처음 여기 왔을때는 말이 올시다. 그래도 1억은 될꺼요.
And she was in school and making no money
이 숙녀분은 학교에 있었는데 돈 한푼 못벌었죠.
What would be your advice for
조언 한번 읊어보소
someone that's new coming to New York
뉴욕에 처음 오는 사람들한테
Come with friends. Be willing to live in like totally X situations
친구랑 같이 와요. 엿 같은 상황에서 살 수 있는 깡있는 놈이랑
and take whatever job that you can
뭐든 그냥 일단 해
Take risks, try new things, push yourself
위험 감소하시고, 새로운 것도 해보시고, 스스로를 갈아넣어요.
You know, think playing it safe in New York
알다시피 뉴욕에서 안전빵만 원하면
doesn't get you very far
얼마안가 고꾸라 질거에요
Are you in Tech or what do you do?
테크쪽이요? 뭐하는 사람입니까?
I was trying to guess.
추측하고 있었는데
Like a designer or architect?
디자이너? 건축가?
No I work in finance
나 금융인데
Oh do you? Do you wear this to work??
오 그래? 근데 옷이 왜이래?
I've worn this to work but I usually wear black pants
이것도 입는데 주로 깜장바지만 입지
What kind of stuff do you do in finance?
금융에서 뭐해요?
Asset Management
자산관리
What are the ranges of salaries that someone could be
연봉이 대략 어떻게 됩니까?
Starting out I think the average wage is like 95k.
시작할때는 아마 1억 3천?
What do you do for work in New York?
뉴욕에서 뭐합니까?
What do you do for work?
뭐하냐구요?
I'm a lawyer
아 난 변호삽니다.
I don't know if I want to be sued by you
너한테 고소 당하고 싶은건지
or have you as like my defense
내 변호를 해주길 바라는지 모르겠지만
what kind of law?
대략 무슨법 합니까?
none of the above yeah
그런건 아니고
I'm a corporate lawyer
그냥 회사 소속 변호삽니다.
What's the range of what a lawyer can make in New York
뉴욕 변호사는 대략 얼마나 법니까?
You do $50,000 to maybe a hundred thousand
7천에서 1억 3천 정도 될 껄
But if you're in the corporate space,
하지만 나같이 멋진 회사 변호사면야
you probably make six figures.
몇억대는 기본이지.
What do you do in New York?
거 뉴욕에서 뭐하고 있습네까?
I'm a composer.
작곡가이올시다
That is so cool, what do you compose?
올 존멋. 뭐 작곡하는디요?
I compose music for a TV
TV 음악 하지
Is there anything that we've we've heard?
우리가 알만한 거라도 있소이까?
There was the opening sequence on Shameless the TV Show.
Shameless TV 쇼 오프닝 내가했지~ 흠흠
What's a top composer make.? I have no idea.
탑 작곡가는 얼마나 법니까. 난 진짜 모르겠는데
Hans Zimmer he makes uh
한스짐머 정도 되면은
quarter billions but then it goes down to
한 몇천억 되려나, 그 나머니 찌끄래기들은
pennies per stream on like Spotify or whatever
한번 듣는데 몇 푼 정도 받겠지, 스포티파이나 뭐 그런것들에서
like 0.0008 cents
0.0008 센트정도?
What kind of work are you in?
어디서 일합니까?
I work in Finance
나도 금융이요.
There is an opportunity in every industry
모든 산업에 기회는 항상 있죠.
How do you think you made it?
어떻게 당신은 성공했죠?
Just hard work. If you like to work, come to New York.
죽어라 일만하죠. 너 일 좋아해? 뉴욕으로 와.
How much work is hard work?
열심히가 도대체 얼만큼이요?
I'm a workaholic but I I think in any field
아 난 워크홀릭인데ㅋㅋ 내 생각엔 어느 분야든
Whether you're a lawyer a banker
법조계던 은행쪽이던
New York City it's a place is a magnet for people
뉴욕 시티는 사람을 끌어들이는 개미지옥 자석 같은 곳 이지
who like to work hard
일 겁나 좋아하는 사람들을
Do you love what you do?
너 너가 하는일 좋아하지?
Yea  I love what I do yeah.
음청
That was great thank you guys so much
그래 진짜 고맙다.
Definitely, a lot of interesting people in New York
정말 뉴욕시티는 흥미로운 사람들이 많네요.
I think one of the common themes from the variety of people
제 생각에 이 사람들에 공통점은 말이죠
that we got to chat with today
오늘 저희가 대화를 나눴던 사람들이요.
was that all of them really said
다들 똑같이 말하네요
You just got to keep going.
정말 쭈우욱 그냥 될때까지 열심히 하라구요.